<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sohaib</title>
    <link>https://sohaib03.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Sohaib</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 01:40:56 +0600</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://sohaib03.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>https://sohaib03.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 01:40:56 +0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sohaib03.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to my personal space! I&amp;rsquo;m a passionate educator, researcher, and developer with a deep love for problem-solving and teaching. My journey has been shaped by diverse experiences, from competitive programming to cutting-edge research, all driven by a desire to learn and share knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I graduated with a BSc in Computer Science and Engineering from Bangladesh University of Engineering and Technology (BUET). Currently, I serve as an adjunct lecturer at BUET, teaching courses such as Software Engineering and Mathematical Analysis for Computer Science. My passion for teaching extends beyond the classroom, as I actively mentor aspiring programmers and help organize contests to inspire students.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>QT-WEAVER</title>
      <link>https://sohaib03.github.io/research/qtweaver/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sohaib03.github.io/research/qtweaver/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Summarizing individual gene trees into species phylogenies using coalescent-based methods has become a standard approach in phylogenomics. However, &lt;strong&gt;gene tree estimation error (GTEE)&lt;/strong&gt;—arising from both analytical factors and biological causes (e.g., short gene sequences)—can adversely impact the accuracy of phylogenomic inference.QT-WEAVER introduces the novel problem of correcting the quartet distribution induced by a set of estimated gene trees.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WQFM-tree</title>
      <link>https://sohaib03.github.io/research/wqfmtree/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sohaib03.github.io/research/wqfmtree/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;wQFM-TREE&lt;/strong&gt; is a summary method developed for species tree estimation from multi-locus data, addressing gene tree discordance. It builds on the wQFM method and improves its scalability, making it applicable to large datasets.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CHIP-8 Emulator</title>
      <link>https://sohaib03.github.io/projects/chip-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sohaib03.github.io/projects/chip-8/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This project is a &lt;strong&gt;CHIP-8 emulator&lt;/strong&gt; written in &lt;strong&gt;Golang&lt;/strong&gt;. The &lt;strong&gt;Ebiten game engine&lt;/strong&gt; was used to create the graphical interface. Developing this project helped me understand how emulators work by simulating the behavior of a physical machine in software.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Yet Another C Compiler</title>
      <link>https://sohaib03.github.io/projects/yet-another-c-compiler/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sohaib03.github.io/projects/yet-another-c-compiler/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This repository contains my implementation of a &lt;strong&gt;C Compiler&lt;/strong&gt;, developed as part of a lab project during my undergraduate studies at &lt;strong&gt;BUET&lt;/strong&gt;. The project encompasses the complete pipeline of compiler construction, progressing through various stages to produce a functional compiler.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>xv6 Operating System Enhancements</title>
      <link>https://sohaib03.github.io/projects/xv6-operating-systems/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sohaib03.github.io/projects/xv6-operating-systems/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This project extends the &lt;strong&gt;xv6 Operating System&lt;/strong&gt;, a simple Unix-like OS developed for educational purposes. The enhancements include the implementation of advanced scheduling algorithms, paging, and file system features. The project was initially developed as part of an operating systems lab, showcasing practical skills in OS development.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
